Courage now, truth always, Batman forever!
Batman Forever is a action, crime, fantasy film directed by Joel Schumacher.
Batman faces off against two foes: the schizophrenic, horribly scarred former District Attorney Harvey Dent, aka Two-Face, and the Riddler, a disgruntled
ex-Wayne Enterprises inventor seeking revenge against his former employer by unleashing his brain-sucking weapon on Gotham City's residents.
As the caped crusader also copes with tortured memories of his parents'
murder, he has a new romance, with psychologist Chase Meridian.
Bruce Wayne / Batman, played by Val Kilmer.
Harvey Dent / Two-Face, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Edward Nygma / The Riddler, played by Jim Carrey.
Dr. Chase Meridian, played by Nicole Kidman.
Dick Grayson / Robin, played by Chris O'Donnell.
Alfred Pennyworth, played by Michael Gough.
Batman Forever is a 1995 American superhero film based on the DC
Comics character Batman by Bob Kane and Bill Finger.
It is the third installment of the Batman film series,
acting as a standalone sequel to Batman Returns.
Directed by Joel Schumacher and produced by Tim Burton and Peter MacGregor-Scott, it stars Val Kilmer as Bruce Wayne /
Batman, replacing Michael Keaton, alongside Jim Carrey, Tommy Lee Jones, Nicole Kidman, and Chris O'Donnell.
The film follows Batman as he attempts to prevent  the Riddler (Carrey) and Two-Face (Jones) from uncovering his secret identity and
extracting information from the minds of Gotham City's residents, while at the same time navigating his feelings for psychologist Dr.
Chase Meridian (Kidman) and adopting orphaned acrobat Dick Grayson
(O'Donnell)—who becomes his partner and best friend, Robin.
Schumacher mostly eschewed the dark, dystopian atmosphere of Burton's films by drawing inspiration from
the Batman comic books of the Dick Sprang era, as well as the 1960s television series.
After Keaton chose not to reprise his role, William Baldwin and Ethan Hawke
were considered as a replacement, before Kilmer joined the cast.
Batman Forever was released on June 16, 1995, to mixed reviews from critics, who praised the visuals, action
sequences, and soundtrack, but criticized the screenplay and tonal departure from the previous two films.
The film was a box office success, grossing over $336 million worldwide
and becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 1995.
It was followed by Batman & Robin in 1997, with Schumacher returning as the director,
O'Donnell returning as Robin, and George Clooney replacing Kilmer as Batman.
The film explores themes of riddle, superhero, villain, rose, based on comic.